（鼻歌）
（続く鼻歌）
（高橋(たかはし)）ハア… あっ
What are you doing?
（高橋）何やってんだ？
（ひかり）おおっ
うん？
ゴクリ
Gulp.
♪〜
I want to talk...
About your Wonderful Original
Interviews with Monster Girls
The class is astir
I want to let myself go too,
But I end up putting on a fake smile.
Your eyes alone conveyed a competitive spirit
Biting at your lip forcefully.
You once said,
"I wouldn't want to worry what someone thinks
And end up hurting someone else in the process!"
When the chime rings out, as the rain lifts up,
We'll pass the boundaries of our school!
Jumping through the puddles, light will scatter about
Our smiles, and wishes will be so bright!
I want to talk...
About your Wonderful Original!
〜♪
Takahashi Tetsuo Wants an Interview
Good morning.
（校長）
ん〜 今日から
新任の先生がいらっしゃるのですが
We have a new teacher joining us today.
Faculty Office
But she doesn't seem to be here
yet, so I'll introduce her later.
どうも まだ来ていないようなので
挨拶は後ほどということで
She must be awfully impressive
to arrive late on her first day.
初日から遅刻とは なかなか…
By the way, Mr. Takahashi...
（加藤(かとう)）そういや 高橋先生って…
Yeah?
（高橋）はい？
（加藤）し〜っ
Well, that's enough joking around.
Earlier, you said you're researching
demi-humans, didn't you?
以前 亜人(あじん)の研究してたって
言ってましたよね
I was thinking of making them the
topic of my college thesis.
大学の卒論のテーマに
しようとしただけですよ
でも
亜人の扱いはデリケートですから
But dealing with demi-humans is always delicate,
so a simple teacher can't get permission.
一介の学生じゃ許可は下りず
結局 今まで 一度も
To this day, I've still never even seen a demi-human.
亜人には お目にかかったことは
ありませんよ
Well, the number of demi-humans is really quite low...
亜人の絶対数は少ないですからね
どうして亜人をテーマに？
Why did you choose them as your topic?
I want to interview demi-humans!
俺は亜人と語りたいんです
あっ はあ…
ん？　どうして そんな話を？
Why do you bring this up?
Oh, well, actually—
ああ いや 実はですね…
I'm sorry I'm late!
（早紀絵(さきえ)）
遅れて申し訳ありません！
Ah, you're here.
（校長）
ああ 着きましたか
どうぞ 前に来て挨拶を
Come up to the front and introduce yourself.
I really am sorry!
（早紀絵）本当にすみませんでした
Um... My train was delayed due to a car inspection, and...
ええと
電車が車両点検で遅れてしまって…
The train I tried to take was very crowded!
乗ろうとした電車が
混んでたんです！
Ah, yes, of course. I understand.
（校長）
ああ なるほど
事情は分かりました
Would you mind introducing yourself?
挨拶 お願いできますか？
Yes, sir!
（早紀絵）はい
遅れたなら分かるけど
混んでたって理由になるのか？
I can understand her being late,
but is a crowded train an excuse?
Well, I suppose she can't help it.
まあ
しょうがないんじゃないですか？
うん？
ああ ですから彼女が…
Oh, what I mean is that she's...
My name is Satou Sakie.
（早紀絵）佐藤(さとう)早紀絵と申します
I'll be teaching math.
担当は数学です
あと 亜人です
Also, I'm a demi-human.
I'm a succubus.
サキュバスです
The new teacher's a demi-human?
（教師）新任は亜人か
Have you ever met one?
I found one.
会えた
In this world,
（ひまり）
この世界には亜人と呼ばれる
特別な性質を持った人間がいる
there are people called "demi-humans" who possess special qualities.
Succubi, vampires, dullahans...
サキュバス バンパイア デュラハン
The demi-humans who have been used as characters in myths and fairy tales.
神話やおとぎ話の
モチーフにもなった亜人
They have also endured persecution in the past.
かつては迫害の歴史もあった
Demi-human Welfare Division
But discrimination has been less common in recent years,
しかし 近年では
不当な差別もみられなくなり
and there's even a welfare system for demi-humans
日常生活に不利な点を持つ
亜人に対する—
who live with any sort of disadvantage.
Demi-human
Division
生活保障制度も存在する
Now, being a demi-human is seen as
just another aspect of one's identity.
今や亜人は
ひとつの個性として認められていた
（生徒たちの話し声）
You can do it.
One, two...
（男子）頑張れ
（男子たち）せ〜の
Lower it a bit more.
（女子）もうちょっと下げて
Did you go anywhere for spring break?
Coming through.
（男子）通りますよ〜
Hey, you two!
（高橋）
ほら そこ
しゃべってないで運べよ
Stop chatting and start carrying!
Okay.
（男子たち）は〜い
So, anyway...
（男子Ａ）でさ…
（男子Ｂ）続けんのかよ
You're gonna keep talking?
（早紀絵）
う〜ん　曲がってないよね？
It isn't crooked... Right?
Ms. Satou.
（高橋）佐藤先生
（早紀絵）はいっ！
Yes?!
C-Can I help you?
な… 何でしょう？
私 生物担当の高橋です
I'm Takahashi, the biology teacher.
高橋先生
Mr. Takahashi...
Yes.
（高橋）
はい　よろしくお願いします
It's nice to meet you.
あっ ええ…
Uh... Same here.
こちらこそ
よろしくお願いしま… いだ！
Nice to meet y— Ow!
No, I mean... Wait!
あっ 違う 待って
あっ ああ〜っ！
（脚立が倒れる音）
Um...
あの… 大丈夫ですか？
Are you all right?
（早紀絵）はい
Yes.
Um, as I said this morning, I'm a succubus.
あの 今朝も言いましたが
自分はサキュバスです
はい　ですから…
Yes, that's why—
That's why I dress and act to avoid
evoking sexual thoughts,
だから なるべく性を想起させない
身なり 振る舞いをして
and refrain from contact with
others as much as possible!
ほかの人との接触も
できるだけ避けてるんです
I'm sorry. I wasn't thinking.
すみません　気が回らなくて
Is it that unusual?
そんなに珍しいですか？
（高橋）えっ
Huh?
I noticed the way you've, um...
私 気付いてました
先生が その…
ずっと遠くから私を見てたこと
been watching me from afar all this time.
Oh... No, that was just...
ああ　いや それは…
興味本位に近づかれると困るんです
It's troublesome if you approach
me purely out of curiosity.
If you'll excuse me.
では 失礼します
Wait, Ms. Satou, you've got it all wrong.
（高橋）
いや 佐藤先生 誤解です
俺は…
I...
（早紀絵）コ〜ッ
Okay, maybe not...
（高橋）いや そうでもないか
I really blew it.
マズったな
A Few Days Later
あっ
Ms. Satou, about the other day...
佐藤先生 先日は…
あっ いえ
No, I should apologize for my indiscretion.
こちらこそ 失礼してしまいまして
すみませんでした
I'm sorry...
I'm fine, so please don't worry about me.
私は大丈夫ですので
お気になさらずに
Sorry, sorry, sorry...
すみません すみません
ハア これじゃ語るどころじゃ…
She'll never talk to me now.
Oh, there he is! Hey!
（ひかり）先生〜！　先生！
Hello! Mister!
（ひかり）先生〜！
（高橋）あっ
うわっ
You're huge!
デカッ！
What are you doing here at this hour?
（高橋）こんな時間にどうした？
忘れ物でもしたのか？
Did you forget something?
（ひかり）
えっ　ああ〜 ハハハ
そういうわけじゃ…
Ah!
N-Not exactly...
Bye!
（ひかり）さよなら！
（高橋）あっ おい！
Hey!
So you're a new student?
（高橋）
新入生だったのか
Yep, I am.
うん そうだよ
そっちも先生だったんだね
And you're a teacher here, huh?
That's right.
（高橋）まっ そういうことだ
What were you doing there before
the entrance ceremony, anyway?
というか 入学前に
あそこで何やってたんだ？
Well... I was trying on my uniform at
home, and I got kind of excited.
いや〜 家で制服 合わせてたら
なんかテンション上がっちゃって
So I thought, "All right! I'm gonna go to school right now!"
よ〜し じゃあ このまま
学校に行っちゃうかって… ノリで
But did you have to run off at top speed like that?
あんな全力で逃げることないだろ
Anyone would run if some weird old guy
they don't know speaks to them.
知らない変なおじさんに
声かけられたら 普通 逃げるでしょ
Weird old guy?
変なおじさん
They taught us that in school.
（ひかり）
学校で そう教えられたもん
先生だったら すぐさま逃げた
この私の冷静な判断と
If you're a teacher,
I think you should praise my calm
decision to flee immediately,
as well as my swift response to the situation!
迅速な行動を もっと褒めて
たたえるべきだと思いますけどね
Anyhow, did you need something?
はっ！
Oh, right! We don't need to talk about me!
ああ そうだ
私の話はどうでもいいの
Um, uh...
え〜と あの…
クラスメイトが具合悪そうなの
My classmate isn't feeling well!
Help me carry her to the nurse's office!
保健室に運ぶの 手伝って！
Okay, I'll be right there... Um...
分かった すぐ行く　え〜と…
Class 1-B, Takanashi Hikari!
（ひかり）
１年Ｂ組 小鳥遊(たかなし)ひかりです！
そうか
Okay, thanks for letting me know, Takanashi.
知らせてくれて ありがとな
小鳥遊
But I hope there's actually some way I can help.
とはいえ 俺が診て
なんとかなるもんだったら
いいんだが
Huh? Are you the health teacher?
あれ？　先生の担当って保健？
No, biology.
いや 生物だが
だてに何年も教師やってないからな
But I'm not a teacher for nothing, you know.
I can judge a student's health with one look at her face.
生徒の具合くらい
顔見りゃ 分かるさ
She has no face!
顔がないんだが
Yeah, I can see that.
見りゃ 分かるよ
So she's basically one of those, right? A dullahan.
だから この子
要するにアレでしょ？　デュラハン
A dullahan?
デュラハン？
A demi-human whose head is separate from its body?
頭と胴体が分離した亜人か
I went ahead and carried her
head to the nurse's office,
頭は私が先に
保健室に運んだんだけど
but her body's too heavy for me.
体は重くって
なるほど
Gotcha.
A second demi-human... I can't believe it.
（高橋）
まさかの亜人 ２人目…
Is it safe to touch this flame?
（高橋）
この火は触れても平気なのか？
Dunno... It doesn't look hot, but...
さあ？　熱くはないみたいだけど
Stretcher coming through!
（佐竹(さたけ)）担架 通るぞ
I'll be okay.
（雪(ゆき)）
大丈夫だから
冷やせば大丈夫だから
I'll be okay once I cool down.
I'm okay...
大丈夫 雪女だから
私 雪女だから…
I'm a snow woman...
I'm a snow woman, so I'm okay.
I'm a snow woman, so it's totally okay...
雪女だから　全然 平気だから
Wow, we've got a snow woman, too?
へえ 雪女ちゃんもいるんだ
Come on, Mr. Takahashi. Let's get to the nurse's office, too.
ほら 先生
私たちも行こう 保健室
R-Right.
（高橋）あっ ああ
Th-Three of them, so easily...
さ… ３人目 こんな簡単に
（ひかり）
でも 最初に見つけたのが
先生でよかったよ
I'm glad you were the first person I found.
I mean, she's pretty big.
その子 結構 おっきいから
Takanashi!
（高橋）小鳥遊
You seem pretty calm about this.
お前 随分 落ち着いてるけど
珍しくないのか？　亜人
Aren't demi-humans unusual to you?
Huh? Well, yeah, I'd say they're unusual,
え〜？
そりゃあ 珍しいとは思うけど
驚きはしないかな
but they don't surprise me.
う〜ん… だってさあ
After all...
私も亜人だし
バンパイアだし
I'm a demi-human, too.
I'm a vampire!
Nurse's Office
ああ… あっ
（戸が閉まる音）
The snow woman has a mild heat exhaustion from P.E. class,
（ひかり）
雪女の子は体育で軽い熱中症
and the dullahan just has a cold.
デュラハンの子は
ただの風邪だって
What's wrong, Mr. Takahashi?
どうしたの？　先生
Just thinking that meeting
demi-humans is easier than I realized.
（高橋）
いや 亜人って
意外に会えるんだなあって
I'm sort of shocked, I guess...
ショックというか なんというか
Mr. Takahashi, do you hate demi-humans?
先生 亜人 嫌いなの？
Oh... No, not at all.
ああ… いや 違う
誤解される言い方をして悪かった
むしろ 亜人は大好きだ
Sorry, I shouldn't have put it that way.
I actually love demi-humans.
Huh? Oh, really?
（ひかり）
えっ？　ああ そう　エヘへ
I've done all kinds of things to try and
meet them, but nothing worked.
今まで
亜人に会おうと いろいろやって
うまくいかなかったもんだからな
I was just thinking about other
stuff besides how happy I am.
うれしさよりも先に
いろいろ考えてしまった　すまん
Sorry.
ふ〜ん
There we go...
うんしょっと
In any case, you're saying you're
happy you met me, right?
とりあえず 私に会えて
うれしいってことでしょ？
（高橋）そうだな
That's right.
Really happy?
（ひかり）すごく うれしい？
Yeah, really happy.
Hee hee hee!
エヘへへ
Ha ha ha. What?
（高橋）アハハハ… 何？
うん　よし
Okay! Well, thanks, Takanashi.
とりあえず ありがとな 小鳥遊
これからよろしく
I'll be seeing you.
Yep! Oh, by the way...
（ひかり）うん！
（ひかり）あっ そうそう
（高橋）うん？
Mr. Takahashi, you call people like us "demi-humans," right?
先生 私たちみたいなのを
亜人って呼ぶでしょ？
ああ
Yeah.
I used the term to go along with you, but it's outdated!
（ひかり）
私も先生に合わせてたけどさ
そもそも その言い方は古い！
Outdated?
（高橋）古い？
"Demi-human" doesn't sound cute at all, does it?
“あじん”って響き
かわいくないでしょ？
N-Not cute?
（高橋）か… かわいくない？
It sounds like it's out of a textbook.
教科書っぽい言葉だし
そりゃあ…
Well...
So high school girls like us
（ひかり）
だから
女子高生とか若い子の間ではね
use "demi" instead!
“デミ”って言うの
Oh...
へえ
Takahashi Tetsuo wants interviews.
（ひまり）
高橋鉄男(てつお)は語りたい
Demi...
デミ
Interviews with monster girls.
Interviews with Monster Girls
（ひまり）
デミちゃんと語りたい
This is why I asked this morning
if you'd forgotten anything!
（ひまり）
だから 朝 聞いたじゃない
忘れ物してない？　って
なに当たり前のように忘れてるのよ
How could you forget it, like it's the obvious thing to do?
そうやって プンプンしてても
But I know you'll lend me yours,
even though you're mad, which is why...
ちゃ〜んと貸してくれる
ひまりのことが…
（ひかり）お姉ちゃん 大好きよ！
（ひまり）ちょっと もう
I love you so much!
You're always pushing your luck, Sister!
調子ばっかりいいんだから
お姉ちゃんは
Sister?
（高橋）お姉ちゃん？
（２人）ん？
あっ 先生
Mr. Takahashi!
ああ 紹介するね
妹のひまり
Oh, I'll introduce you.
This is my little sister, Himari.
I'm Takanashi Himari, from class C.
Ｃ組の小鳥遊ひまりです
双子？
Twins?
Yep, we are.
（ひかり）うん そう
じゃあ これ
Okay, here.
あっ ありがとう！
Thanks!
また落書きしたら承知しないからね
If you doodle in it again, you'll regret it!
Got it.
うい〜っす
If you'll excuse me.
では 失礼します
“ひかり”と“ひまり”か
Hikari and Himari, huh?
誰かさんより全然しっかりしてんな
She seems more responsible
than someone else here.
She's the little sis I'm proud of!
自慢の妹です
あの子は あじ… うっうん！
デミじゃないのか？
Is she also a demi-hum—
A demi?
Nope.
じゃないよ
Oh, by the way...
（高橋）あ〜 そういえば…
What?
何？
Well, uh...
（高橋）あっ いや…
Only if it's okay with you, I mean...
小鳥遊が
嫌じゃなかったらなんだが…
ん？　バンパイアのこと
教えてほしいとか？
You want me to tell you about vampires?
Yeah. Of course, I won't force you.
うん　もちろん無理にとは言わん
できればでいいんだが
Only if you want...
Okay.
いいよ
ああ やっぱりそうだよな…
いいの？
Yeah, that's what I thought— You will?!
Sure.
うん
Then, if I talk to you, can I come and hang out in the biology prep room?
あっ じゃあ 話するから
生物準備室に遊びに行ってもいい？
S-Sure, come by anytime.
おっ おお　いつでも来ていいぞ
やった！
じゃあ 今度 行くね フフッ
Sweet! Okay, I'll be there!
Wow...
（女子Ａ）へえ　じゃあ 町(まち)さん
So, Machi, you went to the middle school right next to mine?
中学 私んとこの隣だったんだ
（町）
この学校に
近所の人がいるとは思わなかったよ
I never expected to meet someone in this school from so nearby.
（女子Ａ）フフ 私も
Me, either.
Then, do you also take the bus, Machi?
（女子Ｂ）
じゃあ
町さんもバスで通学してるの？
No, I walk.
ううん　徒歩だよ
え〜！
あそこから歩きって遠くない？
Really? Isn't that a long walk?
The bus is crowded during school
commuter hours, so it's dangerous.
通学時間のバスは混むから
危ないんだよね
You know, with the way I'm built and all.
ほら 私 こういう体質だから
Uh...
（女子Ｂ）う…
ああ…
Oh! By the way, I found a really funny video yesterday!
あっ そういえば
昨日 面白い動画 見つけたんだ
Yeah? What kind?
（女子Ｂ）へっ へえ どんなの？
Oh, Machi, you watch videos online, too?
あっ 町さんって動画とか見るの？
Yeah, sometimes.
うん　時々
Here, look! This cat is so cute!
（女子Ａ）
ねえ 見て
この猫 超かわいいの
Let me see.
（女子Ｂ）
見せて 見せて！　えっ 何これ
Oh, my god!
Isn't it crazy?!
（女子Ａ）ヤバくない？
That's wild! It's so cute!
（女子Ｂ）超ヤバい！
アハハハハ…
Right?
Demis are more likely to occur as a result of mutation than genetics.
（高橋）
そもそもデミの体質は
遺伝よりも
突然変異によって生じることが多い
It's entirely possible for only one twin to be a demi.
姉だけデミの双子というのも
当然ありうる
The sisters' relationship aside,
そんな姉妹の関係を始め
I still don't know anything about how demis live,
そもそも
亜人として生きている者たちが
どう生き 他人と どう接し
何を思うのか
how they interact with others,
how they think, or anything like that.
そういったことは まだ分からない
Biology Prep Room
ただ ひとつ
分かったことがあるとすれば…
Biology Prep Room
If there's one thing I now know, it's that...
（ひかり）はふ〜
This room is so nice, dark and cool!
この部屋
薄暗くて 涼しくていいよね
...vampires get hot easily.
（高橋）
バンパイアは暑がりだ
This is paradise!
極楽 極楽
I did say you could come by anytime, but...
（高橋）
確かに
いつ来てもいいとは言ったがな
Well, the sunlight is so bright in my classroom.
だって
教室の日差(ひざ)し強いんだもん
And I'd feel bad, making my classmates go out of their way for me...
クラスのみんなに
合せてもらうのも悪いし
Yeah, I guess there are lots of things in here
that shouldn't be in direct sunlight.
まあ ここには
あまり日に当てちゃ良くないもの
たくさんあるからな
Anyway, Mr. Takahashi, you want to
interview a demi, right?
それに先生
デミと語りたいんでしょ？
I charge a venue fee!
場所代 場所代
Hmm...
（高橋）
う〜ん　そういうことなら いっか
In that case, never mind.
ニヒヒッ
Encyclopedia of
Vampires
What do you think of the qualities given to vampires by legends?
Encyclopedia of
Vampires
（高橋）
伝承として伝わってる
バンパイアの性質ってどうなんだ？
Encyclopedia of
Vampires
Let me see!
見せて 見せて！
Hmm... I do like garlic.
う〜ん ニンニクとか好きだしな
Crosses?
十字架？　プハハッ
Crosses are only fashionable through middle school!
十字架ファッションは
中学までだよね〜
Fashionable?
（高橋）ファッション…
Oh! This!
あっ これ！
A stake through the heart would kill us! Probably!
心臓に杭(くい)を打たれると死ぬ！　多分
That would kill me, too.
（高橋）それは俺も死ぬ
Do vampires really have to drink blood to stay alive?
バンパイアって やっぱり
血を飲まないと
生きていけないのか？
No, I don't think that's true.
ううん　そんなことないと思う
（高橋）え？
Huh?
Do you ever get anemic, Mr. Takahashi?
先生 貧血になったりする？
Feel short on blood?
血が足りない！
みたいな感じとか分かる？
Know what I mean?
Well, sometimes, I guess.
ああ たまに　なんとなくは
It's like we often feel that way.
（ひかり）
あれが頻発する感じ
日に当たりたくないのも同じ理由
For that reason, we prefer to stay out of the sun, too.
So if we're careful about what we eat, we can get by just fine.
だから 食べ物に気をつければ
わりと なんとかなるよ
What do you eat?
食べ物？
Liver! I love liver and onions!
レバー！　レバニラとか大好き！
And also tomato juice.
あと トマトジュース
血を飲んでる感あるし
It feels just like drinking blood!
Feels just like drinking blood?
血を飲んでる感ってことは
Meaning that you really do desire blood?
やっぱり
血を飲みたい欲求はあるのか？
ああ… うん　そうかもしれない
Well, yeah... Maybe I do.
Vampires are provided with blood by the government.
バンパイアって
国から血が支給されるの
We get one pack per month.
月１でパックで
Yeah, I'd heard that.
（高橋）ああ それは知ってる
Maybe drinking that makes it so I can get by on the food I eat.
私が食べ物を気をつけるくらいで
済んでるのは
それ飲んでるからかも
う〜ん　なるほど
I see.
Then, there are some vampires who get
by without relying on that blood...
そして その血に頼らずに
生きているバンパイアもいると
Right.
（ひかり）そうそう
What do you think of those vampires?
そういう人たちのことを
どう思う？
What do I think?
どうって…
I think they're pretty amazing!
すげえな〜って
All right, that's enough for today.
じゃ 今日は この辺で
（ひかり）
ああっ 待って！　先生
Wait, M-Mr. Takashi! Give me one more chance, please!
チャンスを！　もう一度 何とぞ
後生ですから
I'll never ask another favor!
Um, um...
え〜と え〜と…
ベジタリアンっているじゃない？
There are vegetarians, right?
Yeah.
（高橋）ああ
They survive without eating meat.
肉 食べないで生きてるんだって
どう思う？
What do you think of that?
What do I think?
どうって…
すげえな〜って
I think they're pretty amazing...
Yes! That! It's like that!
そう それそれ！　その感覚
Wow, I really get it now.
（高橋）
ああ なんか すごい分かった
はあ〜 なるほどね　あっ
I understand...
By the way, do you ever feel the need to take blood directly?
そういえば 直接
人から血を吸いたいと思うのか？
えっ？
Huh?
Stories say people you drink from become vampires
（高橋）
血を吸った相手も
バンパイアになるとか
or that you can make them your servants.
眷属(けんぞく)にできるとかは おとぎ話だが
Isn't that what your fangs are for?
牙は そのためのものだろ？
Ever want to use them to suck blood?
牙 刺して吸いたいと思う？
Yeah, I do! I want to!
うん 思う 思う　吸いたい
ほほう
Oh...
Recently...
（ひかり）最近なら
Oh, you know that snow woman in the class next door?
ほら 隣のクラスに
雪女の子がいるじゃない？
Yeah, the one from the other day.
ああ この間の
Since she's a snow woman, her body feels so cold!
（ひかり）
あの子 雪女だけあって
体 冷たいの
Boom!
Whoa! T-Takanashi?
I can't stand heat, so I cling to her a lot.
This again?
Mm, you feel so cool!
私 暑いのダメだからさ
よく くっついたりするんだけど
Aw, what's the problem? We both hate heat.
And then, when I get a look
at the nape of her neck...
そういうとき
すうっと首筋とかが見えたりすると
But this feels hot to me...
I think, "Ah, her body is cold, but I bet her blood is warm,"
“ああ
この子は体は冷たいんだけど”
“血は あったかいんだろうな”
とか
and "I bet that contrast would feel great if I sucked her blood,"
“血を吸ったら そのギャップが
心地いいんだろうな”とか
and "I'd love to see how she struggles and the pain showing on her face."
“牙を突き立てたときの”
“嫌がったり痛がったりする顔を
見たいな”とか
（ひかり）かぷっ
（雪）ああっ！
そういうことを思うよ
I do think about that.
I don't do it, though, since she'd hate me.
嫌われちゃうから やらないけどね
Huh... That seems a bit erotic.
へえ なんだかエッチっぽいな
R-Really? It does?
そ… そう？　今ので？
Uh, yeah. Guess you weren't aware of it.
（高橋）ああ うん
（高橋）
なんと自覚なし
異性に対しても
吸いたいと思ったりするのか？
Do you ever want to suck the blood of the opposite sex?
思わない
Nope.
No? So you prefer girls' blood?
へえ 女の子の血がいいのか？
Well, not exactly.
いや そうじゃなくて…
I think it's probably because I've never been in love...
それは きっと私が
恋をしたことがないからかなって
はあ… 血を吸う行為は
ある程度 性を想起させる表現で
In a way, sucking blood is an expression of sexual desire.
So fantasizing about sucking girls' blood could pass for a joke,
同性で妄想するのは
冗談で済ませるけど
but you still have some reservations about doing it with boys, huh?
異性に対しては
まだ引け目があるかなということか
Yes, I do! You're too quick on the uptake!
そうよ　察し良すぎるでしょ
Well, not that I'd know, but it seems
like sadistic behavior, right?
まあ まだ分かんないけど
血を吸うって Ｓっぽいじゃない？
And my type is someone who's dependable.
私 頼りがいのある人が
タイプだから
So maybe it would be really hard for me to do that.
そういうの
想像しにくいだけかも… だし
Or something!
What?
何よ
（高橋）いいや 別に何も？
Oh, nothing, really.
Liar! You were thinking it's nice to be young,
ウソ！　若いっていいな〜とか
青春してるな〜とか
or I'm making the most of my youth,
or some other old man's thought!
おっさん目線で思ってたんでしょ！
You're quick on the uptake.
（高橋）察しがいいじゃないか
くっ…
（笑い声）
That's right.
（高橋）
ああ そうだ
バンパイアちゃんは お年頃なのだ
This vampire is at that age.
It was insensitive of me to ask all that...
（高橋）
とやかく聞くのは野暮(やぼ)だったな
I'm the one who said you could ask anything.
何でも聞いてって言ったの 私だし
ふん！
Hmph!
This has been fun. I've learned a lot from you. Thanks.
いろいろ話 聞けて楽しかったよ
ありがとな
Huh? We're done already?
（ひかり）ええっ もう おしまい？
Don't be silly. We have classes next.
バカ言え　次 授業だ
俺もお前も
Both of us.
（チャイム）
See? There's the bell.
（高橋）
ほら 予鈴だ
教室 戻れ　教室〜
Get back to class. Back to class.
う〜ん… は〜い
Yes, sir!
（続くチャイム）
（ひかり）かぷっ　とっとっと…
Whoops...
So, were you surprised? Were you surprised?
ねえねえ 驚いた？　驚いた？
Don't sink your teeth into me, even by mistake.
間違っても歯を立てるなよ？
Hey! That was kinda erotic!
あ〜！
今の なんかエッチっぽい！
アハハハハッ
Bye-bye, Machi.
（女子）町さん バイバイ
うん バイバイ
Oh, bye-bye.
ハア…
Hey, Macchi!
（ひかり）ねえ マッチー
M-Macchi?
マ… マッチー？
ん？　あれ なんか元気ない？
Huh? Are you feeling down?
あっ ううん
全然 そんなことないけど
No, not at all.
マッチーって大変だよね
You have it pretty rough, huh?
うん？
I mean, you have to carry your head
everywhere you go, don't you?
（ひかり）
だってさ
いつでもどこでも 頭 持って
あっちこっち
行かなきゃいけないでしょう？
（町）えっ？
Huh?
Going to and from school must be even worse...
登下校とか
もっと大変そうだもんな
Carrying your bag would take one
hand, so that'd be dangerous.
かばん持っちゃうと
片手 塞がっちゃうから
危なそうだし
What's wrong?
どうしたの？
Not really... I'm used to it.
ううん　私 慣れてるから
Yeah, I guess so.
まあ そりゃ そうか
でも 不便じゃない？
Isn't it inconvenient, though?
ちょっとね
A little.
（ひかり）
ほら 私もバンパイアでしょう？
I mean, I'm a vampire, you know?
So I totally get what you're going through!
だから そういう苦労って
すっごい分かる
Really?
（町）そうなんだ
Yeah, in my case, I can't stand strong sunlight...
（ひかり）
うん　私の場合
日差しが強いのとか
全然ダメでさ
Oh?
（町）へえ
In summer, I can't even wear short sleeves!
（ひかり）
夏でも半袖とか絶対 無理！
But vampires can't stand to be hot, either.
なのにバンパイアは
暑いのも苦手ときたもんだ
Wow, that sounds awful.
（町）うわ〜 それ大変そう
Right?
（ひかり）でしょ〜！
I just want to cover my body in cold compresses!
もうね 体中に
冷却シート貼っときたいくらい
（町）アハハハハッ
What are you two talking about?
（悠子(ゆうこ)）ねえ 何の話？
The injustices of this world.
（ひかり）世の中の不条理について
What does that mean?
（悠子）何それ？
So, Takanashi—
（町）小鳥遊さんって…
Call me Hikari.
（ひかり）ひかりでいいよ
Hikari...
ひかりちゃんって
休み時間 見ないけど
I never see you during breaks.
Do you go somewhere?
どこか行ってるの？
Actually, yeah.
ああ それはね… あっ
ニッヒッヒ
うん？
（ノック）
Come in.
はい どうぞ
（戸が開く音）
うん？
うわ〜！
Let's see...
えっと… 町 京子(きょうこ)だよな？　１Ｂの
You're Machi Kyouko, from 1-B, right?
Er, I guess asking your body's pointless...
って 体に言ってもダメか
あ？
To Mr. Takahashi
I'm so nervous!
（町）緊張する
It'll be fine.
（ひかり）大丈夫だよ　私を信じて
Trust me.
Mr. Takahashi...
（町）
“高橋先生”
Thank you for carrying me to the
nurse's office when I had a cold.
“先日は風邪で倒れたところを
保健室まで運んでいただき”
“ありがとうございました”
Hikari told me about you,
“ひかりちゃんから
先生の話を聞いて”
and I'd be happy to talk to you
about being a demi, too.
“私もデミの話をできたらいいなと
思いました”
I also want to thank you
personally for your help.
“先日のお礼も 直接したいので”
May I come and talk to you sometime?
“今度 お話をしに行っても
いいですか？”
Oh.
あっ でも
体だけじゃ返事 聞けなくない？
But you can't hear his answer
with only your body.
Ah!
（町）あ…
あっ！
I wrote my answer for you.
（高橋）返事 書いたぞ
（２人）わっ！
Carry it back, and don't drop it.
落とさず持ってけよ
Hikari, I did it! I got his answer!
（町）
ひかりちゃん やったよ
返事もらったよ
Yeah! Way to go!
（ひかり）
おお やったね！
じゃなくて 逃げろ〜！
Wait, no! Run!
Hey, wait!
（町）ああ 待って！
フフッ
Whew, that was nerve-wracking...
たは〜 焦った
I was really surprised.
（町）びっくりしたね
What does it say?
（ひかり）どう どう？
Machi
Feel
free
to
come
by
anytime.
Takahashi
Oh! Way to go!
おお やったね！
うん
Yeah.
All right! Let's celebrate!
（ひかり）
よ〜し！　じゃあ お祝いしよう
Celebrate?
（町）お祝い？
Let's stop somewhere on the way
home. We can get drinks!
（ひかり）
帰り どっか寄ろう
お茶しよ お茶！
Oh, okay. That sounds great.
（町）
あっ うん　いいね！
Yay! Where should we go?
What should we drink?
（ひかり）
やった〜！　ねえねえ どこ行く？
何 飲む？
What do you like, Macchi?
あっ マッチーって何が好きなの？
Well...
（町）え〜？
♪〜
The events of a mysterious world,
Like the ones you hear of in fairy tales,
Are actually closer than you think
Just like the way you and I met!
When I stood up tall to gaze at
The familiar scenery outside my window,
Even days that felt like torture seemed precious somehow.
Stuck in my heart, I can't put them into words
How should I try to put these feelings into words?
Laughing over stupid things...
Getting mad over small details...
We'll keep carving these trivial moments into our hearts.
Sometimes I'm feeling sad...
But when I'm with you, I'm so happy!
We'll keep on building these irreplaceable moments,
And little by little, we'll come to understand one another.
〜♪
Next Time
Dullahan Wants to Be Coddled
Next time on Interviews with Monster Girls:
（ひまり）
次回「亜人ちゃんは
語りたい」
Dullahan Wants to Be Coddled.
「デュラハンちゃんは
甘えたい」